A Guide to the Virginia Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council papers, 1970-1982
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council papers, 1970-1982
The Library of Virginia
31486
9 cubic feet (24 boxes and oversize)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the Virginia Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council, Richmond, April-September 1982.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Equal Rights Ratification Council was a coalition of more than thirty organizations in Virginia that supported the Equal Rights Amendment to the U.S. Constitution. Included were education, legal, labor, press, political, and religious groups, and groups comprised primarily of women.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1970-1982, encompassing a comprehensive history of the Equal Rights Amendment, emphasizing the efforts for its passage in Virginia. Includes correspondence, subject files, newspaper clippings, mailing lists, printed material, posters, maps, monaural and video cassette tapes, and ephemera. Material relating to the General Assembly from 1979-1981 concern its actions regarding the Equal Rights Amendment as well as background information on members of the General Assembly during this period. The activities and forms of support for the Equal Rights Amendment by participating organizations are noted, and there are files on the variety of issues which originated as a result of the proposed amendment.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: General Files
Series II: General Assembly
Series III: Elections
Series IV: Mailing Lists
Series V: Organizations, alphabetical
Series VI: Organizations, by type
Series VII: ERA, General Information
Series VIII: ERA, Issues
Series IX: Advertising and Publicity
Series X: Newspaper Clippings
Series XI: Miscellaneous
Series XII: Maps
Series XIII: Publications
Contents List
- Series I: General files, 1979-1981., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  - File Organizing Project. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly Information, General. (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - General Assembly Information, History, ERA. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Assembly Information, Legislative History. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sponsor: House- House of Delegates Information, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rules Change- Jefferson Manual. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Senate- Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - House of Delegates, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Virginia General Assembly, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Officials- State-wide and U.S. Congressional elected. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Senate Bills, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - House Bills, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Headcount- Senate. (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
  - Equal Rights Amendment- Pro. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General Assembly Sponsors- important history information. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Legislative Spouses. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II: General Assembly, 1977-1981., Extent: 5 boxes. (Box 2-6)
  - General information. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Parliamentary procedures. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Privilege and Election Committee and miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Redistricting, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Committees- House. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Biographical facts. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Senate. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Communications with General Assembly. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Republicans. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Committees- Senate. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Targeting- House of Delegates Districts, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Education background. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Military service. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Occupation. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Population data. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Privileges and Elections Committee- House. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Privileges and Elections Committee- Senate. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Seniority- House and Senate. (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - House District 1. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - House District 2. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - House District 3. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - House District 4. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - House District 5. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - House District 6. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - House District 7. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - House District 8. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - House District 9. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - House District 10. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - House District 11. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - House District 12. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - House District 13. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - House District 14. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - House District 15. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - House District 16. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - House District 17. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - House District 18. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - House District 19. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - House District 20. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - House District 21. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - House District 22. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - House District 23. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - House District 24. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - House District 25. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - House District 26. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - House District 27. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - House District 28. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - House District 29. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - House District 30. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - House District 31. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - House District 32. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - House District 33. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - House District 34. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - House District 35. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - House District 36. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - House District 37. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - House District 38. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - House District 39. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - House District 40. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - House District 41. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - House District 42. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - House District 43. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - House District 44. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - House District 45. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - House District 46. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - House District 47. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - House District 48. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - House District 49. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - House District 50. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - House District 51. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - House District 52. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Congressional District I. (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Congressional District I, Schools/libraries. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Congressional District I, Media. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Congressional District I, Civic Groups. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Congressional District I, ERA Supporters (empty). (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Senate District 1. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Senate District 2. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Senate District 3. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Senate District 4. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Congressional District II. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Congressional District II, Mailing lists. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Congressional District II, Civic Groups. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Congressional District II, Media. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Congressional District II, Schools/libraries. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Congressional District II, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Senate Districts 5-7. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Senate District 8. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Congressional District III. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Congressional District III, Civic groups. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Congressional District III, Media (empty). (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Congressional District III, Schools/libraries (empty). (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Congressional District III, ERA supporters. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Permission forms. (Box 4, Folder 28a)
  - Senate District 9. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Senate District 10. (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Senate District 11. (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Senate District 12. (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Congressional District IV. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Congressional District IV, Mailing list. (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Congressional District IV, Civic groups. (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Congressional District IV, Media (empty). (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Congressional District IV, Schools/libraries. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Congressional District IV, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Senate District 13. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Senate District 14. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Senate District 15. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Senate District 16. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Congressional District V. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - House- McDiarmed ERA,1978. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Urban corridor. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Religious affiliate- General Assembly. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Congressional District V. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Congressional District V, Media (empty). (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Congressional District V, School/libraries. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Congressional District V, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Senate District 17. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Senate District 18. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Senate District 19. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Senate District 20. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Congressional District VI. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Congressional District VI, Civic groups. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Congressional District VI, Media (empty). (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Congressional District VI, Schools/libraries. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Congressional District VI, ERA supporters. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Senate District 21. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Senate District 22. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Senate District 23. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Senate District 24. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Congressional District VII. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Congressional District VII, Civic groups. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Congressional District VII, Media. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Congressional District VII, Schools/libraries. (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Congressional District VII, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Senate District 25. (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Senate District 26. (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Senate District 27. (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Senate District 28. (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Congressional District VIII. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Congressional District VIII, Civic groups. (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Congressional District VIII, Media (empty). (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Congressional District VIII, Schools/libraries (empty). (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Congressional District VIII, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Senate District 29. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Senate District 30. (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Senate District 31. (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Senate District 32. (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Senate District 33. (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Senate District 34. (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Senate District 35. (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Senate District 36. (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Congressional District IX. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Congressional District IX, Civic groups. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Congressional District IX, Media (empty). (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Congressional District IX, Schools/libraries. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Congressional District IX, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Senate District 37. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Senate District 38. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Senate District 39. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Senate District 40. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Congressional District X. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Congressional District X, Civic groups. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Congressional District X, Media (empty). (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Congressional District X, Schools/libraries. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Congressional District X, ERA supporters (empty). (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Legislative mailing lists. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Congressional delegation. (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
  - U.S. Senators. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Economic strategies. (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Series III: Elections, 1970-1981., Extent: 1 box. (Box 7)
  - Candidates. (Box 6, Folder 20-21)
  - Election Day Poll (empty). (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Election results, 1981. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Election results, 1979. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Election results, 1978. (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Election results, 1977. (Box 6, Folder 26-28)
  - Election results, 1970-1976. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Candidates who lost. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Non-reelecteds. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Defunct- non-reelecteds. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - House District 36, Chesterfield and Colonial Heights. (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Mailing lists, 1978., Extent: 1 box. (Box 7-8)
  - Congressional Districts V, VI, VII. (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
  - Congressional Districts VIII-X and out-of-state. (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
- Series V: Organizations, alphabetical, 1979-1980., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 8-10)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha (empty). (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - American Association of Business Women. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW). (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - American Bar Association - Virginia State. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - American Camping Association (empty). (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU). (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - American Psychological Association. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Church Women United. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Common Cause. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Federally Employed Women. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Girl Scouts. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Gray Panthers. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Homemakers Equal Rights Association (HERA). (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - League of Women Voters. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Men for ERA. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mormons for ERA. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - National Association of Business and Professional Women's Clubs. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - National Association of Social Workers. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW). (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - National Secretaries Association. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - National Women's Party. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Richmond Women's Bar Association. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Sociologists for Women in Society. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Commission on the Status of Women. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Council on Social Welfare. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Council on State Legislation. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Virginia ERA Political Action Committee (VERA-PAC). (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Home Economics Association. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Nurses Association. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Women Attorneys Association. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Women's Political Caucus (VWPC). (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Women's Clubs, General Federation of; Virginia Federation. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Women's Equity Action League. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Women's Forum, Martinsville (empty). (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Women's Lobby, Inc.. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Women's Lobby of Virginia, Inc.. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Women USA, Inc.. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Young Women's Christian Association (YMCA). (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
  - Zonta International (empty). (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Organizations, by kind, 1977-1980., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 10-12)
  - Subseries 1. Black.
    - Black Caucus. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP). (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - National Black Feminist Organization. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - National Council of Negro Women. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Washington Urban League (empty). (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 2. Chamber of Commerce.
    - Directory of Virginia Chambers of Commerce, statewide. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 3. Educational.
    - General. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - American Association of University Professors (AAUP). (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Southern Woman's Educational Alliance. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Educational Institutions. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Commonwealth University students. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Education Association (VEA). (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 4. Legal.
    - General. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Mary & William Women's Law Society. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - National Association of Women Lawyers. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - University of Virginia Law Women. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous legal. (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Subseries 5. Labor.
    - General. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - AFL-CIO Industrial Organizations. (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Amalgamated Meat cutters and Butcher Workers of North America. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Bakery and Confectionary Workers International Union of America. (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Communications Workers of America. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (empty). (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - American Newspaper Guild. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers, Local 172. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - United Auto Workers. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Coalition of Labor Union Women. (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Labor for Equal Rights Now (LERN). (Box 10, Folder 38-40)
  - Subseries 6. Media/Press.
    - National Publications and Media Groups. (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Press/Media, Video tape. (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - American Newspaper Women's Club. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - American Women in Radio and Television. (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Press Women. (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Women in Communications, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Independent Virginian. (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Subseries 7. Political.
    - General. (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Democrats. (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Republicans for ERA. (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Republicans. (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Women, General. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - National Women's Education Fund. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mayors. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Democratic State Central Committee. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - White House. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 8. Professional.
    - Health and Welfare. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Libraries, public, private and endowed. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 9. Scientific.
    - General. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Neuropsychiatric Society of Virginia (empty). (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 10. Religious.
    - Religious Committee, Virginia. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Congress of Women's Organizations. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - General. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Roanoke Valley Ministers Conference. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Catholic Women for ERA. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Catholics Act for ERA. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Council on Women and the Church. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Evangelicals for Social Action. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Inter faith Council for Richmond Area Church Women. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - International Association of Women Ministers. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Religious Committee for the ERA. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Southern Christian Leadership Council (SCLC). (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Council of Churches. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Baptists. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - American Baptist Women. (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Southern Baptists. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Call to Action Conference. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Christian Feminists. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Catholic. (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Leadership Conference of Women Religious. (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Good Shepherd's Catholics for Shared Responsibility. (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - National Coalition of American Nuns. (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - NETWORK- Association of Nuns. (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Office of Social Development. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Priests for Equality (empty). (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Quixote Center. (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - St. Joan's International Alliance. (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Sisters of Mercy. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Sisters of St. Joseph. (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Social Ministry Commission. (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Jewish (empty). (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Methodist (empty). (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Annual Conference- United Methodist Church (UMC). (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Board of Church and Society (UMC). (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Commission on Status and Role of Women (UMC). (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - ERA Support Project (UMC). (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - United Methodist Women. (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Presbyterian. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Women's Concerns- Presbyterian. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Synod- Presbyterian Church. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Synod Mission Council- Presbyterian (empty). (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - United Presbyterian Church USA; Albert Currie Winn. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Other [denominations]. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Christian Church (Disciples of Christ). (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Church of the Brethren. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Friends Committee on National Legislation (FCNL). (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Lutheran Church in America (LCA). (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Lutheran Church Women. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Mormons for ERA. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Unitarian-Universalist Women's Federation. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - United Church of Christ. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Quarterly Meeting of Friends (empty). (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Subseries 11. Miscellaneous.
    - Coalitions, General. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Coalitions, Local ERA Coalitions. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Coalitions, Local Organizations. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Coalitions, Fairfax County Democratic Women's Caucus. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Coalitions, Peninsula. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Coalitions, Rockbridge. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Coalitions, Shenandoah Valley (VERA). (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Coalitions, Tidewater ERA Council. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Coalitions, Valley Citizens for the ERA. (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Coalitions, Williamsburg Committee for ERA. (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - International Toast mistresses. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Federation of Colored Women's Clubs. (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - General Assembly- Senate. (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - General Assembly- House of Delegates. (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - General Assembly, General. (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - International Women's Year (IWY). (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Republican Party. (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Del. Thomson- VERA-PAC. (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Virginia Politics. (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Education discrimination. (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Elections. (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Equal Rights Amendment. (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - House Sponsors. (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Discrimination complaints. (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - National Advisory Committee for Women. (Box 12, Folder 41)
- Series VII: Equal Rights Amendment, General information, 1978-1981., Extent: 1 box. (Box 13)
  - General. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - National ERA Ratification Council, 1978. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - National ERA Support lists. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Other State Newsletters, 1981. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - ERA in other states, general. (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - ERA in other states, California. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - ERA in other states, Colorado. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - ERA in other states, Indiana. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - ERA in other states, Kentucky. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - ERA in other states, Maryland. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - ERA in other states, Massachusetts (empty). (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - ERA in other states, Michigan. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - ERA in other states, New Mexico. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - ERA in other states, Oklahoma. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - ERA in other states, Pennsylvania. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - ERA in other states, Texas. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - ERA in other states, Washington. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, general. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Arizona. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Arkansas. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Florida. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Georgia. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Illinois. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Louisiana. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Missouri. (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Nevada. (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, North Carolina. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Oklahoma. (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, South Carolina. (Box 13, Folder 30)